<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Page 45 &#8211; British Comics</title>
	<atom:link href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/feed/?paged=45" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Comics from the UK</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='britishcomics.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>https://s0.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Page 45 &#8211; British Comics</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="British Comics" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Hubbard, Mike</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/hubbard-mike/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/hubbard-mike/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MIKE HUBBARD (2 April 1902, Ireland &#8211; 25 June 1976) was born ERNEST ALFRED HUBBARD in Dublin, Ireland. He came to London after World War I and there he attended art school and joined Dean&#8217;s Studio as an illustrator. He started out as an illustrator on the British story papers of the Amalgamated Press in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="54833" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/hubbard-mike/mike-hubbard/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg" data-orig-size="500,380" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Mike Hubbard" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54833 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=336&#038;h=255" alt="" width="336" height="255" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=336 336w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 336px) 100vw, 336px" /></a></p>
<p>MIKE HUBBARD (2 April 1902, Ireland &#8211; 25 June 1976) was born ERNEST ALFRED HUBBARD in Dublin, Ireland. He came to London after World War I and there he attended art school and joined Dean&#8217;s Studio as an illustrator. He started out as an illustrator on the British story papers of the Amalgamated Press in the 1930s, including The Thriller and Detective Weekly.</p>
<p>Hubbard moved into comics after the Second World War. He continued to work for AP, making adaptations of &#8216;Treasure Island&#8217;, &#8216;The Coral Island&#8217;, &#8216;The Adventurs of Robin Hood&#8217;, &#8216;Sinbad the Sailor&#8217;, &#8216;The Adventures of Marco Polo&#8217; and &#8216;Red River&#8217; for Knockout in the second half of the 1940s.</p>
<p>He additionally was Norman Pett&#8217;s assistant on the daily &#8216;Jane&#8217; comic strip for the Daily Mail, starting in 1946. Hubbard took over completely in 1948 and turned the comic into an early soap series. He kept it running until 1959, when he made Jane and her lover live happily ever after.</p>
<p>By the early 1960s, Hubbard started working for the Fleetway girls&#8217; titles. He drew strips based on pop songs for Valentine, the serial &#8216;Nurse Angela&#8217; in Princess and strips like &#8216;Annette in Wartime France&#8217;, &#8216;Angel of the Backstreets&#8217; and &#8216;The Peewit Gang&#8217; for Schoolgirl&#8217;s Picture Library. One of his best-known works is however &#8216;Jane Bond, Secret Agent&#8217;, that appeared in Tina and Princess Tina between 1967 and 1970. He then did full colour novel adaptations for Ranger, Look and Learn and Pixie in the late 1960s and early 1970s. He died on 25 June 1976.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/hubbard-mike/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/mike-hubbard.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Belardinelli, Massimo</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/belardinelli-massimo/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/belardinelli-massimo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MASSIMO BELARDINELLI (5 June 1938 – 31 March 2007) was an Italian comic artist best known for his work in the British science fiction comic 2000 AD. Belardinelli was born in Rome. His father was an amateur oil painter. Inspired by the Disney film Fantasia, Belardinelli went into animation in the 1960s, painting backgrounds for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="54832" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/belardinelli-massimo/massimo-belardinelli/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg" data-orig-size="500,419" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Massimo Belardinelli" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54832 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=347&#038;h=290" alt="" width="347" height="290" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=347 347w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 347px) 100vw, 347px" /></a></p>
<p>MASSIMO BELARDINELLI (5 June 1938 – 31 March 2007) was an Italian comic artist best known for his work in the British science fiction comic 2000 AD.<br />
Belardinelli was born in Rome. His father was an amateur oil painter. Inspired by the Disney film Fantasia, Belardinelli went into animation in the 1960s, painting backgrounds for films produced by the Sergio Rosi studio. He then moved into comics, again through the Rosi studio, drawing backgrounds for &#8220;The Steel Claw&#8221; in the British weekly Valiant in a team which also included Giorgio Cambiotti on pencils and Sergio Rosi himself on inks. In 1969 he moved to the Giolitti Studio, which got him work in Italy, Germany, the UK and the USA. He collaborated with Alberto Giolitti on Gold Key Comics&#8217; Star Trek series in the USA, with Giolitti drawing the characters and Belardinelli the spaceships. In the UK in the mid-70s he drew &#8220;Rat Pack&#8221; for Battle Picture Weekly and &#8220;Death Game 1999&#8221; and &#8220;Green&#8217;s Grudge War&#8221; for Action.</p>
<p>When 2000 AD was in preparation in 1977, an artist was needed for the revamped &#8220;Dan Dare&#8221;, and Belardinelli tried out for no pay and got the job, and the rare honour of a byline, despite editor Pat Mills&#8217; reservations: although he excelled at visualising aliens, alien technology and alien landscapes, Mills thought &#8220;the hero looked awful&#8221;. Belardinelli&#8217;s work on the strip was not popular, and after a year he was switched to future sports series &#8220;Inferno&#8221;, the sequel to the popular &#8220;Harlem Heroes&#8221;, while former &#8220;Harlem Heroes&#8221; artist Dave Gibbons took over &#8220;Dan Dare&#8221;.<br />
Belardinelli then drew the second series of &#8220;Flesh&#8221;, in which the time-travelling meat-farmers moved into the prehistoric oceans, in 1978-9. He also drew &#8220;The Angry Planet&#8221;, a sci-fi serial set on colonised Mars, written by Alan Hebden, for Tornado in 1979, and then took over &#8220;Blackhawk&#8221;, Gerry Finley-Day&#8217;s strip about a Nubian slave who became a Roman centurion, when Tornado merged into 2000 AD later in the year. The strip was given a sci-fi twist by new writers Alan Grant and Kelvin Gosnell, with the hero being abducted by aliens and forced to fight in a galactic arena. Grant believes the strip&#8217;s popularity was down to Belardinelli&#8217;s art.</p>
<p>&#8220;Meltdown Man&#8221;, a year-long cliffhanger serial written by Alen Hebden, followed in 1980-81, in which an SAS officer was caught in a nuclear explosion and blasted into a future where humans have enslaved genetically-engineered humanoid animals, and leads the fight for their liberation. In 1981 writers John Wagner and Alan Grant created a new series for him, space haulage comedy &#8220;Ace Trucking Co.&#8221;. Grant says they wanted to exploit Belardinelli&#8217;s &#8220;fevered imagination&#8221; and wrote a series which featured &#8220;as few actual human beings as possible&#8221; &#8211; almost all the characters were aliens.<br />
Belardinelli also drew several storylines of the Celtic barbarian strip &#8220;Sláine&#8221; in 1983-84, whose writer, Pat Mills, selected him to visualise the hero&#8217;s body-distorting &#8220;warp spasm&#8221;. Although his strips were popular with the general readership, the fan audience never really took to him, and his &#8220;Sláine&#8221; stories were not collected by Titan Books.</p>
<p>His last major 2000 AD strips were &#8220;The Dead&#8221;, written by Peter Milligan (1987) &#8211; a philosophical yet psychedelic series set in a future where an evolved human race thinks it has conquered death, until demons start erupting from their bodies, and the hero, Fludd, has to travel to the land of the dead to save mankind &#8211; violent future sport series &#8220;Mean Team&#8221; (1985, 1987), and space opera &#8220;Moonrunners&#8221; (1988–89). He also drew &#8220;Joe Alien&#8221; for short-lived younger-readers sci-fi comic Wildcat, in 1988. Among his last comic work in the UK was for Fleetway&#8217;s Teenage Mutant Hero Turtles comic in the early 1990s.<br />
He stopped working in British comics in 1993 when his agent, Alberto Giolitti, died. Having suffered from heart problems, Belardinelli died on 31 March 2007.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/belardinelli-massimo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/massimo-belardinelli.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stringer, Lew</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/stringer-lew/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/stringer-lew/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LEW STRINGER (born 22 March 1959 in England) is a freelance comic artist and scriptwriter. Stringer began his career from the late 1970s with a series of fanzines, many featuring his popular Brickman character; these were read by several professional creators (including Kevin O&#8217;Neill, Alan Moore and Dave Gibbons) who encouraged Stringer to try comics [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="54831" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/stringer-lew/lew-stringer/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg" data-orig-size="500,383" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Lew Stringer" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54831 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=347&#038;h=266" alt="" width="347" height="266" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=347 347w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 347px) 100vw, 347px" /></a></p>
<p>LEW STRINGER (born 22 March 1959 in England) is a freelance comic artist and scriptwriter.<br />
Stringer began his career from the late 1970s with a series of fanzines, many featuring his popular Brickman character; these were read by several professional creators (including Kevin O&#8217;Neill, Alan Moore and Dave Gibbons) who encouraged Stringer to try comics as a profession and Stringer recalls that &#8220;Alan Moore actually introduced me to one of the editors at Marvel UK – Bernie Jaye who was editor on The Daredevils&#8221;.</p>
<p>He sold his first professional cartoon to Marvel UK (the British branch of Marvel Comics) in 1983 where it appeared in The Daredevils comic, after which he worked for a short time as art assistant to the cartoonist Mike Higgs (creator of Moonbird and The Cloak). Since then Stringer has freelanced for numerous British comics for various companies and audiences.<br />
His best remembered creations are Tom Thug and Pete and His Pimple for Oink! comic (1986), which outlasted that comic and continued into Buster comic, and Combat Colin the halfwit hero who featured in Action Force and The Transformers comics. Prior to Colin joining Transformers, Stringer had written another, similarly slapstick, strip Robo-Capers for that title. Robo-Capers was replaced by Combat Colin when the reprints of American G.I. Joe strips were added to the Transformers comic. Robo-Capers returned for a single story, which featured Colin and his sidekick, in Issue No. 200. After a change of editorial direction in 1991, Marvel UK handed the rights of Combat Colin to Stringer and he has used him in small-press titles, such as the Combat Colin Special and Yampy Tales. On 30 September 2012, Combat Colin returned in an all-new story for the launch of new David Lloyd&#8217;s new online comic Aces Weekly and two other new stories featuring the character have appeared there since.<br />
Stringer has also worked as a writer on CiTV Tellytots; was one of the main writers on Sonic the Comic, where he created several fan-favourite characters and stories; and has been a long time artist/writer for Viz and many other publications. He has written Toxic!&#8217;s Team TOXIC! strip since the first issue (and drawn it since issue 15); this proved popular enough with the readers to gain two pages an issue and lead to other comic strips being brought in.<br />
In October 2012 reprints of Team Toxic began to appear in the magazine but brand new stories Started to appear from January 2014.</p>
<p>He broke into the international market in 1997 creating the Suburban Satanists for the Norwegian comic Geek. From 1999 to 2007 those characters appeared in the Swedish comic book Herman Hedning.<br />
In April 2005, Active Images published a collection – Brickman Begins – of all of Stringer&#8217;s Brickman strips since 1979. In 2006, a brand new Brickman series began in the American comic book Elephantmen, published by Image Comics, and in 2007, Combat Colin became a guest star in the strip. Brickman seems to be Stringer&#8217;s most enduring character. The series concluded in Elephantmen No.24 in 2009. In September 2015 Stringer reprinted all 20 episodes in a self-published comic entitled Brickman Returns.<br />
He began freelancing for The Beano in 2007, drawing a Fred&#8217;s Bed story for the Christmas issue and a one-off Ivy the Terrible strip for an issue in 2008. In October 2008 Stringer became the artist on a new strip, Super School which is about five superhero children and their non-superpowered teacher. He started drawing for The Dandy after its revamp in October 2010, providing the illustrations for Postman Prat and Kid Cops and writing and drawing The Dark Newt.<br />
In 2014 Lew announced that he would be contributing a regular new cartoon strip to Doctor Who Magazine.<br />
In recent years Lew has scripted and illustrated Rasher and Joe King (The Beano) for The Beano and in 2018 began work on a revival of Big Eggo for that comic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/stringer-lew/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lew-stringer.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sullivan, Lee</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/sullivan-lee/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/sullivan-lee/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LEE SULLIVAN trained as a wildlife and technical illustrator at Barnfield College, then spent five years as a graphic artist for British Aerospace in Stevenage, England. He then became a freelance artist for advertising agencies and magazines, before entering the comics field in 1988. Since, he has worked on such titles as &#8216;Transformers&#8217; (UK run), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54830" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/sullivan-lee/lee-sullivan/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg" data-orig-size="500,649" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Lee Sullivan" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=231" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54830 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=269&#038;h=349" alt="" width="269" height="349" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=231 231w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=269 269w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=116 116w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 269px) 100vw, 269px" /></a></p>
<p>LEE SULLIVAN trained as a wildlife and technical illustrator at Barnfield College, then spent five years as a graphic artist for British Aerospace in Stevenage, England. He then became a freelance artist for advertising agencies and magazines, before entering the comics field in 1988.</p>
<p>Since, he has worked on such titles as &#8216;Transformers&#8217; (UK run), &#8216;Thundercats&#8217;, &#8216;Deathshead&#8217;, &#8216;RoboCop&#8217;, &#8216;Blacknight&#8217; and &#8216;Doctor Who&#8217; for both the British and the American market. Sullivan is also active as an illustrator for educational publications and as a storyboard artist for the BBC.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/sullivan-lee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/lee-sullivan.jpg?w=231" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reid, Ken</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/reid-ken/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/reid-ken/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Often cited as one of Britain’s greatest comic book illustrators, KEN REID was born in Manchester in 1919. An avis artist from an early age, Ken was constantly drawing, even when confined to bed for six months after developing a tubercular hip at the age of nine. After leaving school at the age of thirteen, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54829" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/reid-ken/ken-reid/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg" data-orig-size="500,561" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Ken Reid" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=267" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54829 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=297&#038;h=334" alt="" width="297" height="334" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=267 267w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=297 297w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=134 134w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 297px) 100vw, 297px" /></a></p>
<p>Often cited as one of Britain’s greatest comic book illustrators, KEN REID was born in Manchester in 1919.</p>
<p>An avis artist from an early age, Ken was constantly drawing, even when confined to bed for six months after developing a tubercular hip at the age of nine.</p>
<p>After leaving school at the age of thirteen, he won a scholarship to Salfod Art School.</p>
<p>His father, who had always offered Ken a tremendous amount of encouragement, became his agent and got his son an interview over at the Manchester Evening News.</p>
<p>Ken submitted several strip ideas for the children’s section of the newspaper, which led to them commissioning The Adventures of Fudge the Elf.</p>
<p>Originally appearing in 1938, Fudge’s adventures were published right the way through to 1962, only stopping in 1941 during WWII until 1946 when Reid was de-mobbed.</p>
<p>In the 1950’s, Ken was courted by Scottish publishers D.C.Thomson (his brother-in-law, Bill Holroyd was already working for them), where he starting working on a new strip for The Beano called Roger the Dodger.</p>
<p>Grandpa, Jonah and other strips followed in The Dandy.</p>
<p>Then in the 1960’s, Ken and another member of the British comics royalty – Leo Baxendale, left the company to work for Odhams Press on the new titles Smash and Wham!</p>
<p>A major draw for Ken was that he was being allowed to both write and illustrate for these titles.</p>
<p>It was at Odhams on such strips as Frankie Stein, The Nervs and Dare-a-Day Davy that Ken really got to show off his skill at drawing the beautifully grotesque that he would later become synonymous with.</p>
<p>Dare-a-Day Davy was particularly great. About a schoolboy who couls never say no to a challenge, readers were encouraged to send in a dare and if selected would be paid a pound for their contribution. This led to 86 strips including a Marvel crossover (of sorts) with Nick Fury and an unpublished episode featuring Frankiestein that ended up in the pages of Weird Fantasy magazine.</p>
<p>In the 1970’s, Ken created his most popular character working for IPC. First published in the pages of Jet, Faceache became an instant fan favourite. The adventures of Ricky Rubberneck and his malleable mush ran through Jet and into Buster when the two titles merged. Faceache (Ricky Rubberneck) was a strip that Ken both wrote and illustrated (though Ian Mennell wrote two of the early instalments).</p>
<p>In 1978, Ken’s brilliance was recognised when he was presented with two awards by the Society of Strip Illustration – Cartoonist of the Year and Humorous Script Writer of the Year.</p>
<p>His great work continued through to the next decade where he worked on strips such as Robot Smith, Martha’s Monster Make-Up and Tom Horror’s World.</p>
<p>He passed away on 2nd February 1987 whilst working on a page of Faceache.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/reid-ken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/ken-reid.jpg?w=267" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baxendale, Joseph Leo</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/baxendale-joseph-leo/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/baxendale-joseph-leo/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JOSEPH LEO BAXENDALE (27 October 1930 – 23 April 2017) was an English cartoonist and publisher. Baxendale wrote and drew several titles. Among his best known creations are the Beano strips Little Plum, Minnie the Minx, The Bash Street Kids, and The Three Bears. Baxendale was born in Whittle-le-Woods, Lancashire, and was educated at Preston [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54828" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/baxendale-joseph-leo/joseph-leo-baxendale/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg" data-orig-size="500,269" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Joseph Leo Baxendale" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54828 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=375&#038;h=201" alt="" width="375" height="201" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=375 375w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></a></p>
<p>JOSEPH LEO BAXENDALE (27 October 1930 – 23 April 2017) was an English cartoonist and publisher.</p>
<p>Baxendale wrote and drew several titles. Among his best known creations are the Beano strips Little Plum, Minnie the Minx, The Bash Street Kids, and The Three Bears.</p>
<p>Baxendale was born in Whittle-le-Woods, Lancashire, and was educated at Preston Catholic College.</p>
<p>After serving in the RAF, he took his first job as an artist for the local Lancashire Evening Post drawing adverts and cartoons.</p>
<p>In 1952, he began freelance work for the children’s comic publishers DC Thomson, creating several highly popular new strips for The Beano including Little Plum, Minnie the Minx (started in 1953, taken over by Jim Petrie in 1961), The Three Bears, and The Bash Street Kids (initially called When the Bell Rings).</p>
<p>Baxendale also co-operated on the launch of D.C. Thomson’s The Beezer comic in 1956.</p>
<p>Baxendale’s time with D.C. Thomson came to an abrupt end in 1962 when, overburdened with work he, in his own words, “just blew up like an old boiler” and left.</p>
<p>In 1964, Baxendale began work for Odhams Press as they set up a new children’s comic Wham! and, two years later, its sister comic Smash!</p>
<p>Beginning in 1966 Baxendale worked for Fleetway (IPC Magazines), creating Clever Dick and Sweeny Toddler.</p>
<p>Baxendale left the world of mainstream British children’s comics in 1975, creating the more adult-orientated Willy the Kid series, published by Duckworths.</p>
<p>In the 1980s he fought a seven-year legal battle with D.C. Thomson for the rights to his Beano creations, which was eventually settled out of court.</p>
<p>His earnings from that settlement allowed Baxendale to found the publishing house Reaper Books in the late 80s. In the same year he brought out THRRP!, an adult comic book.</p>
<p>For a year before he fully retired from cartooning to focus on publishing in 1992, Baxendale drew I Love You Baby Basil! for The Guardian.</p>
<p>Baxendale was the second person inducted into the British Comic Awards Hall of Fame, in 2013.</p>
<p>He was described as having created “a lifetime of original, anarchic, hilarious and revolutionary comics” and having had an “incalculable” influence on children and comic artists, while his work was lauded for being “an integral and inseparable part of the history of British children’s comics.”</p>
<p>The BBC said that he was “regarded by aficionados as one of Britain’s greatest and most influential cartoonists” and quoted the British cartoonist Lew Stringer as saying that Baxendale was “quite simply the most influential artist in UK humour comics”.</p>
<p>In the mid-1960s, Baxendale published a weekly anti-war newsletter the Strategic Commentary.</p>
<p>Though it had some paying subscribers, including fellow Vietnam War opponent Noam Chomsky, Baxendale made a considerable loss from sending hundreds of free weekly copies to Labour MPs.</p>
<p>Leo Baxendale and his wife Peggy had five children including Martin Baxendale who also became a cartoonist and worked on some of his father’s strips.</p>
<p>Leo Baxendale died on 23 April 2017 of cancer at the age of 86.</p>
<p>Andy Fanton, who at the time of Baxendale’s death was the Beano’s writer for several Baxendale-created strips, lauded his predecessor as “the godfather of so much of what we do”.</p>
<p>Over the course his career, Baxendale worked for a number of different publishers, writing and drawing many different strips in several different comics.</p>
<p>As well as creating new strips, Baxendale also worked on pre-existing properties, such as Lord Snooty in Beano issues 691–718.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/11/baxendale-joseph-leo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/joseph-leo-baxendale.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stokes, John</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/stokes-john/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/stokes-john/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Discovering his love of comics through reading The Eagle, JOHN STOKES would later join his brother George at IPC, where he worked on several strips for Buster including, Maxwell Hawke, Lennie the loner and no less than three strips that were written by Scott Goodall – The War Children, Fishboy and Marney the Fox. In [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54827" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/stokes-john/john-stokes/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg" data-orig-size="500,626" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="John stokes" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=240" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54827 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=285&#038;h=356" alt="" width="285" height="356" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=240 240w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=285 285w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=120 120w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 285px) 100vw, 285px" /></a></p>
<p>Discovering his love of comics through reading The Eagle, JOHN STOKES would later join his brother George at IPC, where he worked on several strips for Buster including, Maxwell Hawke, Lennie the loner and no less than three strips that were written by Scott Goodall – The War Children, Fishboy and Marney the Fox.</p>
<p>In the seventies he moved to Marvel UK and worked on The House of Hammer, Black Knight in Hulk Weekly, Doctor Who Monthly and Star Wars amongst others (he collaborated with Alan Moore several times in the latter two titles).</p>
<p>As well as illustrating several Future Shocks in 2000 AD, Stokes has worked on many US comics, including L.E.G.I.O.N., Aliens: Havoc, Randy Bowen’s Decapitator and The Invisibles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/stokes-john/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-stokes.jpg?w=240" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Geering, John Keith</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/geering-john-keith/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/geering-john-keith/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John K. Geering (9 March 1941 &#8211; 13 August 1999) JOHN KEITH GEERING was one of the notable artists for British children&#8217;s comic magazines during the 1970s and 1980s. He has worked extensively for the DC Thomson magazines Sparky, The Topper, Cracker, Plug, Nutty, The Beano and The Dandy, for which he created features like [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54826" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/geering-john-keith/john-keith-geering/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg" data-orig-size="500,261" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="John Keith Geering" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class="wp-image-54826 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=377&#038;h=197" alt="" width="377" height="197" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=377 377w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 377px) 100vw, 377px" /></a></p>
<p>John K. Geering (9 March 1941 &#8211; 13 August 1999)</p>
<p>JOHN KEITH GEERING was one of the notable artists for British children&#8217;s comic magazines during the 1970s and 1980s. He has worked extensively for the DC Thomson magazines Sparky, The Topper, Cracker, Plug, Nutty, The Beano and The Dandy, for which he created features like &#8216;Puss &#8216;n&#8217; Boots&#8217;, &#8216;Smudge&#8217; and &#8216;Bananaman&#8217;. The latter gained such popularity that it was turned into an animated TV series. He also drew the Robert Nixon creation &#8216;Gums&#8217; for Buster magazine by Fleetway, and was a topical and political cartoonist for British newspapers. Geering, who lived in Comberbach, passed away in 1999 at the age of 58. His last new creation was &#8216;Dean&#8217;s Dino&#8217; for The Beano.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/geering-john-keith/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-keith-geering.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oliver, John Edward</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/oliver-john-edward/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/oliver-john-edward/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JOHN EDWARD OLIVER (19 June 1942 – 26 May 2007) was a British cartoonist. He is more usually known as J. Edward Oliver or JEO, and to his friends he was Jack. He originally achieved fame in late 1970 with a long-running strip in the UK music paper Disc (and Music Echo), later Record Mirror. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54825" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/oliver-john-edward/john-edward-oliver/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg" data-orig-size="500,282" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="John Edward Oliver" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class=" wp-image-54825 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=376&#038;h=212" alt="" width="376" height="212" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=376 376w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 376px) 100vw, 376px" /></a></p>
<p>JOHN EDWARD OLIVER (19 June 1942 – 26 May 2007) was a British cartoonist. He is more usually known as J. Edward Oliver or JEO, and to his friends he was Jack.</p>
<p>He originally achieved fame in late 1970 with a long-running strip in the UK music paper Disc (and Music Echo), later Record Mirror. The strip had many fans including John Lennon and Yoko Ono. It included characters from TV, film and music, with a large section for readers&#8217; contributions (Win a Plastic Warthog). Jack provided other material, including a pop-based strip called The Nose, stories and numerous graphics.</p>
<p>One character proved particularly enduring, a dinosaur called Fresco-Le-Raye. Up to his death, J Edward Oliver continued to create Fresco strips which can be seen on his official website. (The site also features other strips, such as The Invisible Man, a staple of his Record Mirror years, with Young Julie, The Invisible Woman and more.)</p>
<p>In November 1977, the Record Mirror strip was deemed not contemporary enough and was ended. Oliver went to work for IPC Magazines Ltd, creating comic strips including Buster&#8217;s Master Mind (1980-1983), Cliff Hanger (1983-1987) and Vid Kid, as well as drawing The Champ in Whizzer and Chips from 1979 to 1981. Many of his strips included puzzles and games. In 1984, Oliver also wrote the words for a musical called Swan Esther which was performed at London&#8217;s Young Vic and on BBC radio.</p>
<p>When Buster ceased publication at the beginning of 2000, Oliver was the last artist left, and drew the only non-reprint material in the comic&#8217;s final issue (&#8220;How It All Ends&#8221;, which looked back at how all the Buster characters ended). With Buster gone, Oliver investigated other work, including newspaper strips and first day covers. In 2000, with his cousin [Steve Oliver], and together they created Phil Stamp Covers for stamp collectors. Other work included promotional art for a single by Terry Dactyl and the Dinosaurs.</p>
<p>Among Oliver&#8217;s trademarks in his strips were little signs reading &#8220;Abolish Tuesdays&#8221; and regular sightings of a tiny cube with a crank handle attached. The latter was never explained. Oliver also had something of an obsession with the British actress Madeline Smith, drawing several appearances by her into his work, which she later complained about. Oliver reacted characteristically, producing a strip about her complaint.</p>
<p>In 2000, a website about Oliver&#8217;s work revived interest in it. The site was originally created as a celebration of JEO&#8217;s work in Disc and Record Mirror but JEO contributed new material, as well as obscure historical stuff and a new, e-mailed (and free) weekly strip involving Fresco-Le-Raye, which eventually had hundreds of subscribers and ran for several hundred episodes, eventually developing from black-and-white to colour.</p>
<p>In 2007 Oliver announced he was suffering from cancer, but he continued to create new material. In March 2007 he married his girlfriend of many years, Liz Hales. He died peacefully on 26 May 2007.</p>
<p>JEO&#8217;s website continues, with much unpublished material finally seeing the light of day.</p>
<p>A rare collection of early Middle Bronze Age (c. 13th century B.C.) tools and weapons was discovered by John Oliver whilst digging the footings of an extension to his home in Tredegar Road, Dartford, in 1986. The four implements comprised two axe-heads, a knife and a tanged shaving razor and are known as the Leyton Cross Bronzes. The items were purchased by and are on display in Dartford Museum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/oliver-john-edward/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-edward-oliver.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Petrie, Jim</title>
		<link>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/petrie-jim/</link>
					<comments>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/petrie-jim/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[boutje777]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 17:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishcomics.wordpress.com/?p=54908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[JIM PETRIE was born in Dundee, Scotland, and worked for DC Thomson and its magazine The Beano for forty years. He was an art teacher at Dundee&#8217;s Kirkton High School when he took over the &#8216;Minnie the Minx&#8217; comic from its creator Leo Baxendale in June 1961. Petrie drew over 2000 stories with this rebellious [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="54824" data-permalink="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/petrie-jim/jim-petrie/" data-orig-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg" data-orig-size="500,278" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Jim Petrie" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=500" tabindex="0" role="button" class="wp-image-54824 aligncenter" src="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=357&#038;h=199" alt="" width="357" height="199" srcset="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=300 300w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=357 357w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=150 150w, https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 357px) 100vw, 357px" /></a></p>
<p>JIM PETRIE was born in Dundee, Scotland, and worked for DC Thomson and its magazine The Beano for forty years.<br />
He was an art teacher at Dundee&#8217;s Kirkton High School when he took over the &#8216;Minnie the Minx&#8217; comic from its creator Leo Baxendale in June 1961.<br />
Petrie drew over 2000 stories with this rebellious girl until his retirement in January 2001, and thus defined the character for generations of readers. &#8216;Minnie the Minx&#8217; is currently continued by other artists.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/2018/07/10/petrie-jim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		
		<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9f195c0dd4326a5de41b0d3931dcddaeb0437fe6f3d9dccb07da4ed9ea6810f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boutje777</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://britishcomics.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jim-petrie.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
